coinlib.io 2019-04-16

# Coinlib privacy policy

## Purpose

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to describe how Coinlib ("us," "we," or "our") collects, uses and shares information about you through our online interfaces (e.g., websites and mobile applications) owned and controlled by us, including coinlib.io (collectively referred to herein as the "Site"). Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do. If you do not understand any aspects of our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at [info+privacy@coinlib.io](mailto:info+privacy@coinlib.io). Your use of our Site is also governed by our Terms of Use. 

If you reside or are located in the European Economic Area ("EEA") Coinlib is the data controller of all Personally Identifiable Information (as defined below) collected via the Site and of certain Personally Identifiable Information collected from third parties, as set out in this Privacy Policy. 

## What Information this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers information we collect from you through our Site. Some of our Site's functionality can be used without revealing any Personally Identifiable Information. In order to access certain features and benefits on our Site, you may need to submit, or we may collect, "Personally Identifiable Information" (i.e., information that can be used to identify you). Personally Identifiable Information can include information such as your email address, among other things. You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to Coinlib. Inaccurate information may affect your ability to use the Site, the information you receive when using the Site, and our ability to contact you. For example, your email address should be kept current because that is one of the primary manners in which we communicate with you. 

## What You Agree to by Using Our Site

Please understand that by submitting any Personally Identifiable Information to us, you consent and agree that we may collect, use and disclose such Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, and as permitted or required by law. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personally Identifiable Information, we may not be able to provide you with the services that can be offered on our Site. Consent can be withdrawn at any time by navigating to your profile page and clicking the box to remove consent or deleting your account. Please note that we may also rely on legitimate interests or fulfilment of a contract to continue processing your data. 

## What Information We Collect

We gather two types of information about users through the Site: 

* Information relating to your use of our Site. When users come to our Site, we may track, collect and aggregate information indicating, among other things, which pages of our Site were visited, the order in which they were visited, when they were visited, and which hyperlinks were "clicked." We also collect information from the URLs from which you linked to our Site. Collecting such information may involve logging the IP address, operating system and browser software used by each user of the Site. We may be able to determine from an IP address a user's Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. We also use (or may use) cookies and web beacons when you visit our Site. For more information on our use of cookies and web beacons, please refer to our Cookie Policy. 
* Personally Identifiable Information provided directly by you or via third parties. We collect Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to us when you register for an account, update or change information for your account, complete a survey, sign-up for email updates or Alerts, send us email messages, and/or participate in other services on our Site. We may use the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to respond to your questions, provide you the specific services you select and email messages about Site maintenance or updates. 

Account Registration. If you register for an account on our Site, you may be required to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information such as a username and email address. 

Updates. Coinlib may offer you the ability to receive updates either via email or by posting on portions of the Site only accessible to registered users. In order to subscribe to these services, you may be required to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information such as your name and email address. 

Communications with Coinlib. We may receive Personally Identifiable Information when you send us an email message or otherwise contact us. 

Third Party Sites. We may receive Personally Identifiable Information when you access or log-in to a third party site, e.g., Facebook, from our Sites. This may include the text and/or images of your Personally Identifiable Information available from the third party site. 

Surveys. We may receive Personally Identifiable Information when you provide information in response to a survey operated by us. This may include details about your race, your education history, and your employment. 

## How We Use the Information

Information relating to your use of our Site. We use information relating to your use of the Site to build higher quality, more useful services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our users, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of our Site. We may also use this information to ensure the security of our services and the Site. 

Personally Identifiable Information provided directly by you or via third parties. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, Coinlib will not disclose any of your Personally Identifiable Information. In addition to the other uses set forth in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose and otherwise use Personally Identifiable Information as described below. 

Providing the Site and our services. We use Personally Identifiable Information which you provide to us in order to allow you to access and use the Site and in order to provide any information, products or services that you request from us. 

Updates. We use Personally Identifiable Information collected when you sign-up for our various email or update services to send you the messages in connection with the Site. We may also archive this information and/or use it for future communications with you, where we are legally entitled to do so. 

Communications with Coinlib. When you send us an email message or otherwise contact us, we may use the information provided by you to respond to your communication and/or as described in this Privacy Policy. We may also archive this information and/or use it for future communications with you where we are legally entitled to do so. 

Government Authorities, Legal Rights and Actions. Coinlib may share your Personally Identifiable Information with various government authorities in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights or to protect our property; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. We also may share your Personally Identifiable Information when we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of Coinlib, the Site, our users, customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Use and other agreements. 

Disclosure to Acquirers. Coinlib may disclose and/or transfer your Personally Identifiable Information to an acquirer, assignee or other successor entity in connection with a sale, merger, or reorganization of all or substantially all of the equity, business or assets of Coinlib to which your Personally Identifiable Information relates. 

## External Links

For your convenience we may provide links to sites operated by organizations other than Coinlib ("Third Party Sites") that we believe may be of interest to you. We do not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to these Third Party Sites without obtaining your consent. We do not endorse and are not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Sites. If you choose to click on a link to one of these Third Party Sites, you should review the privacy policy posted on the other site to understand how that Third Party Site collects and uses your Personally Identifiable Information. 

## Retention of Personally Identifiable Information

If you reside or are located in the EEA, we keep your Personally Identifiable Information for no longer than necessary for the purposes for which the Personally Identifiable Information is processed. The length of time we retain Personally Identifiable Information for depends on the purposes for which we collect and use it and/or as required to comply with applicable laws and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights. 

## Confidentiality & Security of Personally Identifiable Information

We consider the confidentiality and security of your information to be of the utmost importance. We will use industry standard physical, technical and administrative security measures to keep your Personally Identifiable Information confidential and secure and will not share it with third parties, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, or unless such disclosure is necessary in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others, as permitted by applicable law. Because the Internet is not a 100% secure environment we cannot guarantee the security of Personally Identifiable Information, and there is some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way to circumvent our security systems or that transmission of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that e-mails communications are typically not encrypted and should not be considered secure. 

## Updating or Deleting Your Personally Identifiable Information

You have certain rights in relation to your Personally Identifiable Information. You can access your Personally Identifiable Information and confirm that it remains correct and up-to-date or choose whether or not you wish to receive material from us or some of our partners by logging into the Site and visiting your user profile page. 

If you would like further information in relation to your rights or would like to exercise any of them, you may also contact us via [info+privacy@coinlib.io](mailto:info+privacy@coinlib.io). If you reside or are located in the EEA, you have the right to request that we: 

* provide access to any Personally Identifiable Information we hold about you 
* prevent the processing of your Personally Identifiable Information for direct-marketing purposes 
* update any Personally Identifiable Information which is out of date or incorrect 
* delete any Personally Identifiable Information which we are holding about you 
* restrict the way that we process your Personally Identifiable Information 
* provide your Personally Identifiable Information to a third party provider of services 
* provide you with a copy of any Personally Identifiable Information which we hold about you. 

We try to answer every email promptly where possible, and provide our response within the time period stated by applicable law. Keep in mind, however, that there will be residual information that will remain within our databases, access logs and other records, which may or may not contain your Personally Identifiable Information. Please also note that certain Personally Identifiable Information may be exempt from such requests in certain circumstances, which may include if we need to keep processing your Personally Identifiable Information to comply with a legal obligation. 

When you email us with a request, we may ask that you provide us with information necessary to confirm your identity. 

## Questions, Suggestions and Complaints

If you have any privacy-related questions, suggestions, unresolved problems, or complaints you may contact us via [info+privacy@coinlib.io](mailto:info+privacy@coinlib.io). 

If you reside or are located in the EEA, our Data Protection Officer and Privacy Team may assist with all queries regarding our processing of Personally Identifiable at [info+privacy@coinlib.io](mailto:info+privacy@coinlib.io). 

## International Privacy Practices

Coinlib's Sites are primarily operated and managed on servers located and operated within the United States. In order to provide our products and services to you, we may send and store your Personally Identifiable Information (also commonly referred to as personal data) outside of the country where you reside or are located, including to the United States. Accordingly, if you reside or are located outside of the United States, your Personally Identifiable Information may be transferred outside of the country where you reside or are located, including to countries that may not or do not provide the same level of protection for your Personally Identifiable Information. We are committed to protecting the privacy and confidentiality of Personally Identifiable Information when it is transferred. If you reside or are located within the EEA and such transfers occur, we take appropriate steps to provide the same level of protection for the processing carried out in any such countries as you would have within the EEA to the extent feasible under applicable law. 

## Changing Our Privacy Policy

Please note that we review our privacy practices from time to time, and that these practices are subject to change. Any change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on our Site. We will notify you of any material change to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on our Site's homepage for a reasonable period of time following such update, and by changing the effective date (located at the bottom of this page). Be sure to return to this page periodically to ensure familiarity with the most current version of this Privacy Policy. 

## No Information from Children Under 16

Coinlib strongly believes in protecting the privacy of children. In line with this belief, we do not knowingly collect or maintain Personally Identifiable Information on our Site from persons under 16 years of age, and no part of our Site is directed to persons under 16 years of age. If you are under 16 years of age, then please do not use or access this Site at any time or in any manner. We will take appropriate steps to delete any Personally Identifiable Information of persons less than 16 years of age that has been collected on our Site without verified parental consent upon learning of the existence of such Personally Identifiable Information. 

Coinlib ("us", "we", or "our") uses cookies on coinlib.io and affiliated websites (collectively the "Site"). Our Cookies Policy explains what cookies are, how we use cookies, how third-parties we partner with may use cookies on the Site, and your choices regarding cookies. Please read this Cookies Policy in conjunction with our Privacy Policy, which sets out additional details on how we use personally identifiable information and your various rights. 

## What are cookies

Cookies are small pieces of text sent by your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Site or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Site more useful to you. Essentially, cookies are a user's identification card for the Coinlib servers. Web beacons are small graphic files linked to our servers that allow us to track your use of our Site and related functionalities. Cookies and web beacons allow Coinlib to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience on our Site. 

Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies. 

## How Coinlib uses cookies

When you use and access the Site, we may place a number of cookies files in your web browser. 

Coinlib uses or may use cookies and/or web beacons to help us determine and identify repeat visitors, the type of content and sites to which a user of our Site links, the length of time each user spends at any particular area of our Site, and the specific functionalities that users choose to use. To the extent that cookies data constitutes personally identifiable information, we process such data on the basis of your consent. 

We use both session and persistent cookies on the Site and we use different types of cookies to run the Site: 

* Essential cookies. Necessary for the operation of the Site. We may use essential cookies to authenticate users, prevent fraudulent use of user accounts, or offer Site features. 
* Analytical/performance cookies. Allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors and see how visitors move around the Site when using it. This helps us improve the way the Site works. 
* Functionality cookies. Used to recognise you when you return to the Site. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name, and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of theme). 
* Targeting cookies. Record your visit to the Site, the pages you have visited, and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the Site and the more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose. 

## Third-party cookies

In addition to our own cookies, we may also use various third-party cookies to report usage statistics of the Site and refine marketing efforts. 
* Tracking cookies. Follow on-site behavior and tie it to other metrics allowing better understanding of usage habits. 
* Optimization cookies. Allow real-time tracking of user conversion from different marketing channels to evaluate their effectiveness. 
* Partner cookies. Provide marketing conversion metrics to our partners so they can optimize their paid marketing efforts. 

## What are your choices regarding cookies

If you'd like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help pages of your web browser. 

Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use some or all of the features we offer. You may not be able to log in, store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly. 

_Last updated: May 14, 2018_

You need an account in order to star coins, keep track of your portfolio, set up alerts, vote on coins as well as use all the other advanced features. 

#### BTC

1MhJJKDEdRTPjDK6oRjq7LYF8nvc6nwT9X  

#### ETH

0x878330469300301859ca7549869b66e98a08511c  

#### LTC

LLpKbWkJ8FUtvzRdj8wgwBYu3XyBVmqMSL  

#### BCH

qq6cc539pekzs9hhjekrptecd8u9umfpjgf85tyy6e  

#### DASH

XnePqvwndoiKUmpwccZ8qtGjF6BBAwj6xD  

#### ETC

0xb45b3de6780a07cacde2249df4a5068bd10860f4  

#### XVG

DBgKdG6SwwvY85VeKrp6VkxBjXGZnKhsta  

For the last 18 months, we have enjoyed working relentlessly to build a service we feel the crypto community deserves. Your __was and still is, our main fuel.

**If you've enjoyed using Coinlib and want to help us turn it into a sustainable project, please help us spread the word!**

  * Tell your friends about Coinlib!
  * Tweet about Coinlib!
  * Share it on Facebook, Reddit, Telegram, Discord or any other forum you think is relevant!
